Raúl Calderón

Full-Stack Developer with experience in PHP focused on AI

Raúl Francisco Calderón Rochín

Hermosillo Sonora, MX.

+52 644 143 9913 raul41092@gmail.com

Online Resume

in Linkedir



About me

Full-Stack developer with nearly 10 years of experience in PHP, WordPress, and complex web development. I'm currently transitioning to creating solutions with Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning using Python. Passionate about continuous improvement, code efficiency, and problem-solving with real impact. I'm open to new opportunities where I can contribute my experience in web development while applying artificial intelligence to automate and optimize processes.

Skills

Backend & Web

-> PHP -> Python

-> Javascript -> CMS (WordPress/Drupal)

-> Ajax -> MySQL

-> API/API REST

Frontend

-> HTML -> CSS

-> Bootstrap -> JQuery

AI (Intermediate)

- -> AI Foundamentals (ML, DL, AI Ethics & Responsible AI)
- -> Machine Learning Tools (Python for AI/ML, Scikit-learn, Pandas & NumPy, Jupyter Notebook)
- -> Generative AI & NLP (Prompt Engineering, AI Agents, NLP, Text Generation & Analysis)
- -> Cloud & Deployment (Oracle Cloud AI Services, AWS, API Development for AI, Containerization Docker)

Version Control

-> Git

Work history

Powdevs - BillingTree | A REPAY Company / Full Stack Developer

- Optimized the generation of daily financial reports in XML/PDF, improving processing speed by refactoring queries and backend.
- Participated in debugging critical payment issues in production, applying version control and traceability best practices.
- Participated in the development and implementation of new features such as secure authentication using email codes (2FA).

Rivka Development - Sales Simplicity Software, Inc. / Full Stack Developer

2019 - 2020

- Developed feature enhancements for a custom WordPress plugin called "Options Online," used on the residential sales site Sales Simplicity (USA).
- Implemented XML scripts to automate the export of property data (prices, availability, etc.), facilitating the management and updating of real estate inventory.

Vagapp Soluciones / Full Stack Developer

2015 - 2019

- I was responsible for the development and support of web projects for clients in Mexico, implementing customized solutions in CMS such as Drupal and full-stack technologies.
 Some of my most notable projects include:
- WedProduction: A social network-style wedding platform, developed from scratch in Drupal. It allowed for quotes, event creation, vendor profiles, and more.
- VisitMexico: An informational site that centralized all tourism and cultural events in the State of Mexico.
- Arizona Driver Club (AZ Drivers): A platform for quoting and comparing different auto insurance plans.

Education

Instituto Tecnológico de Sonora (ITSON) / Software Engineer

2011 - 2015

The career was completed in that period of time.

_

Languages

- Spanish (native)
- English (advanced)

Personal Projects

Create Playlist on Spotify Based on emotions with Al.

Remove replicated songs in a playlist on Spotify with Al.

Chat App with Go, Vuejs and Socket.io

AND MORE

_

Courses and Certificates

Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Generative AI Professional.

The course was taken on Oracle Platform.

Oracle Cloud Infrastructure AI Foundations Associate.

The course was taken on Oracle Platform.

Python For Data Science - Machine Learning with Python.

The course was taken on Desafios Latam.

AI & ChatGPT From Zero to Advanced.

The course was taken on Udemy.

Git Certification.

The course was taken on Desafios Latam.

More relevant certificates